Carmine Montalto

Creative Director at Carmine Montalto, Ink.

carmnyc@gmail.com

Summary

WHO I AM. I'm Carmine Montalto. And I am honored to have this opportunity to present myself and my life's work. My experiences have engendered three strengths – my crafts, really: Branding. Naming. Concepting. How? Well, to start, I am a linguist. My love of language began with my studies of Latin as a teenager. I leveraged that into a degree in English and would go on to teach English grammar for three years. Stepping outside of my own language has given me insights into its structure and conventions that are unique to foreign language study. They enrich and inform my copywriting every day. I love to write. I've been a copywriter for 19 years, non-stop. I've created appealing call-to-action headlines for NYC subway campaigns. Named hundreds of consumer products. And written and honed brand concepts from their genesis to market launch. And I've loved every single word of it. I've recently begun to take up screenwriting, something new and exciting for me! I am awestruck by our innate desire to characterize things, to want to make them sexy and appealing. To create freely and unfettered – and then, to take hold of those unwieldy creations and make them neat and tidy. To wrap them all up in a product name: Coca-Cola Blak. iPod. Facial Fuel (okay, that one's mine!). I love brand voices. To me, the most successful brands – the true culture leaders – are those that speak clearly to their audiences, that beckon and captivate; they're magnetic, yet surprisingly familiar. They're trusted and authentic. Like your coolest, most reliable friend. Brands like that are pretty rare. Because a consistent, trusted brand voice takes ownership, commitment and longevity. For 12 of those 15 years, I have defined, evolved, and vocalized two strong brand voices: Kiehl's Since 1851 and the AIDS Rides. They are among my finest works, my proudest career accomplishments.

Specialties

Concept writing, brand voices, product naming and labeling, brand videos, trademarking, creative, art directing, advertising (headlines/taglines/body copy), script writing, voice-over, dynamic presentation. I travel frequently - particularly to emerging markets in Asia, Africa and South America - to keep my perspective fresh, my talents honed, and my knowledge of industry trends current.

Experience

Creative Director at Carmine Montalto, Ink.

May 2008 - Present (7 years 3 months)

I'm versed in brand identity through execution of clear and consistent brand voices. I provide expert copywriting services including: concept development, product naming, label/packaging writing, and content development for print and Web (SEO-optimized). For each brand I support, I bring a level of expertise and cohesion in its voice that's required to maintain its distinct identity and appeal. With two

decades of copywriting experience, I impart a fervent passion for my work and extensive knowledge of my craft with a rare, genuine sense of ownership. Brands I am currently working on -- or have supported: KIEHL'S SINCE 1851 www.kiehls.com THE NEW YORK TIMES www.nytimes.com KEVYN AUCOIN www.kevynaucoin.com SEPHORA www.sephora.com PETER THOMAS ROTH www.peterthomasroth.com STRIVECTIN www.strivectin.com RALPH LAUREN www.ralphlauren.com MAKE UP FOR EVER www.makeupforever.com LANCOME www.lancome-usa.com ESTEE LAUDER www.esteelauder.com GOOD SKIN LABS www.goodskinlabs.com ANTHONY LOGISTICS www.anthony.com ELIZABETH ARDEN www.elizabetharden.com LIVING PROOF www.livingproof.com OJON www.ojon.com OUIDAD www.ouidad.com ILUMINAGE www.iluminagebeauty.com I retain NDAs with each.

5 recommendations available upon request

Screenwriter at Carmine Montalto, Ink.

June 2012 - January 2015 (2 years 8 months)

Collaborated with Zeric Seymor-Armenteros, New York-based actor and screenwriter, on the screenplay "Boys Will Be Boys." Set in New York City, it's the story of two brothers learning how to love and understand each other after the younger of the two discovers he has a sibling upon the death of their father.

Assistant Vice President, Brand Voice and Identity at Kiehl's Since 1851

May 2002 - May 2008 (6 years 1 month)

In a senior role within the global brand division, I directed the voice and identity of the iconic Kiehl's Since 1851 brand. I maintained ownership of the unique and distinct "voice of Kiehl's", assuring continuity of brand identity while evolving communications and image. • Directed strategic expansion with Sr. team to grow Kiehl's in global markets and maintain unique company values and service traditions; • Wrote, edited, directed all copy to support 2 divisions with separate marketing, sales, PR teams; conceived and oversaw campaigns to optimize launches and initiatives across platforms; • Named more than 150 products, wrote labels for 30+ formulas yearly; partnered with Legal to assess risk and secure trademarks to strengthen brand equity; • Maintained a clear, consistent brand voice with synergies between Kiehl's historic, "cult" products and new formulas/categories; • Lead, developed copy team; established systems to control project flow, adherence to timelines.

9 recommendations available upon request

Senior Copywriter at AEGON

December 2001 - May 2002 (6 months)

Transamerica is a division of Aegon Corporation, one of the premier insurance and financial services companies in the world. Transamerica Retirement Services provides retirement plan solutions to over 10,000 clients nationwide, with over \$8.6 billion in assets under management. As Senior Copywriter, I wrote and edited copy for marketing materials in three distinct voices directed at separate audiences. I lead the creative team that developed concepts from inception through implementation and on-time completion.

Senior Copywriter at Pallotta TeamWorks

February 1995 - December 2001 (6 years 11 months)

Pallotta TeamWorks was a for-profit corporation of 250 employees specializing in the creation and production of multi-day, outdoor events that raised money for charitable causes, including AIDS and breast cancer. TeamWorks revolutionized the way money is raised for charity by applying "big ad agency thinking" to its non-profit event marketing. As Senior Copywriter, I wrote and edited the majority of campaign materials – from major metro advertising to grassroots outreach initiatives. I managed the editing division of the creative department and art directed designers' work to develop highly effective, targeted campaigns to meet aggressive company objectives.

1 recommendation available upon request

Teacher at International School of Languages

September 1997 - August 2000 (3 years)

The International School of Languages is a private institute which caters to the Asian markets, with particular emphasis on Japan. As an ESL instructor, I taught four levels of English – from basic language introduction to advanced grammar and essay writing. Teaching ESL, I gained particular insights into the structure of English grammar and conventions – unique to foreign language study – which continue to enrich and inform my copywriting.

Projects

Portfolio

May 2008 to Present

Members: Carmine Montalto

View my portfolio at www.carminemontalto.com

Languages

French (Limited working proficiency)

Spanish (Limited working proficiency)

Latin (Limited working proficiency)

Courses

BA, English

Assumption College French Grammar Latin

Independent Coursework

Spanish

Advertising Writing

Skills & Expertise

Copywriting

Concept Development

Product Naming

Advertising

Social Media

Creative Direction

Digital Marketing

Marketing Communications

Brand Management

Digital Strategy

Packaging

Fashion

Art Direction

E-commerce

Marketing

Brand Development

Email Marketing

Product Development

Strategy

Magazines

Creative Strategy

Integrated Marketing

Video

Editing

Content Strategy

Branding & Identity

Education

CBEST: Teaching Standards Test

1995 - 1995

Assumption College

BA, English, 1983 - 1987

Activities and Societies: Cum laude

Carmine Montalto

Creative Director at Carmine Montalto, Ink.

carmnyc@gmail.com



15 people have recommended Carmine

"I have had the opportunity to work with Carmine at Kiehl's and then as the CEO of a start-up beauty company called Living Proof. What's been great about that experience is that I've been able to see him contribute to our copy strategy in two distinctly different companies with distinctly different visions & brand attributes. A few things about Carmine that make him a great resource for any company. 1. He was able to strongly contribute to the copy strategy of my start-up company. He wasn't just a writer pushing out copy for collatoral or a web site, he actually helped form our voice and how we talk to our customers. That's a very rare quality to find. 2. He's fast and delivers on-time, all the time. This has been true of both my work with him at Kiehl's and now at Living Proof. Again, rare to find in a creative resource. 3. His work is always well done and he is a good partner with "clients". He takes feedback really well, incorporates it and believes that revisions are important to making the final end product amazing. 4. He likes to contribute to ideas outside his area. So whether its new product development ideas, advertising campaigns or how to organize a company, Carmine has great ideas. All in all, I highly recommend Carmine for anyone looking for a fantastic creative resource in your organization."

— **Rob Robillard**, was Carmine's client

"Carmine has an innate skill for coming in and quickly grasping a brand's essence. Working with him closely at Jurlique, I was always impressed by how he could distill brand identity better than people who had been there for years. His ability to refine complex messages into easily comprehensible marketing copy is simply superb. What's more, Carmine is an "intangibles" guy in that, as valuable as his talent as a wordsmith is to your brand, his value proposition is so much more than that. Carmine has a positive energy about him that can be – and is - infectious to your entire organization."

— **Jeremy Goldman**, *Senior Global Marketing Manager, Interactive, Jurlique*, worked directly with Carmine at Carmine Montalto, Ink.

"Carmine is an incredibly talented copywriter; one of the best I've worked with in the cosmetics industry. As a Product Developer, I had the pleasure of working closely with Carmine at Kiehl's on a multitude of cosmetic product concepts, packaging copy and product related communications. He never failed to impress me with his work and quick turnaround while working within tight deadlines and juggling an enormous workload. He most recently was hired as a Consultant for a brand I work on at the Estee Lauder companies.

Carmine has the unique capability of being able to grasp a brands DNA as well as understand what a Marketer is looking for from him. He also possesses the rare skill of creating a brand personality were non exists capturing the consumers attention and consistently delighting with his written word Simply said, Carmine "gets it' and delivers with incredible creative talent that is brand relevant and appropriate."

— Andrea Phillips, Executive Director Global Product Development, Estee Lauder, worked with Carmine at Carmine Montalto, Ink.

"I was blessed with the opportunity to work with Carmine on Living Proof. Never before have I seen such energy, excitement and positivity about writing. He is nothing short of a joy to be around and to work with. Carmine exercises the utmost professionalism when presented a task, and is driven to wordsmithing perfection. I encourage anyone to take Carmine for a test drive to see what he can do for your brand."

— Erin Josepho, Account Manager, Wolff Olins, worked directly with Carmine at Carmine Montalto, Ink.

"The role of the "voice" of a brand cannot be understated. This most valuable asset to any company-indeed the communication of its personality--is key to achieving the emotional connection that so many businesses seek with their customers (not to mention their employees). I have had the distinction of working directly with Carmine Montalto when he held this position at Kiehl's, which was during our most important developmental years--wherein we went from a company with one free-standing store, to the global reach and nearly 100 Kiehl's stores that we have today. Carmine completely embodied the role of "voice" of our company in every written missive he created, and by dint of the quality and passion of his work, he quickly became the author of virtually all of our communication, from our product labels to our in-store signage to our Web site. Carmine's creativity is uniquely impressive in that his work is not only extraordinarily quickly executed--and always with topnotch quality--but also consistently in the tone and manner that is uncannily representative of the company for which he is writing. I have witnessed this ability firsthand as Carmine has moved into consulting work during this past year, and I now continue to work with him in that capacity, as do other companies who have sought both his talented writing as well as his sage business and communication expertise. I give Carmine my highest recommendation as a Brand Voice Consultant and would be happy to be contacted directly to discuss my professional experiences with him in more detail, if desired."

— Cammie Cannella, was Carmine's client

"Carmine is truly one of the most talented people I have ever worked with. It is not only a pleasure to work with him but an inspiration as well. Now we work together on a freelance basis and Carmine is efficient and a true professional. I cannot recommend Carmine highly enough to any company that would be interested in working with this talented man. Sincerely, Charlotte Adjchavanich"

— Charlotte Adjchavanich, Vice President Global Public Relations & Communications, Kiehl's Since 1851, worked directly with Carmine at Kiehl's Since 1851

"Carmine has the innate ability to take information from wildly varying sources, distill its critical essence, and then convey a focused message in language both pointed and rich. The banter that comes with it along the way is just an added bonus. Straightforward, reliable, intelligent, funny, interesting and interested -- I recommend him without exception."

— **Elizabeth Lamont**, *Vice President, International Development, Kiehl's Since 1851*, worked directly with Carmine at Kiehl's Since 1851

"Carmine and I have had tremendous synergies working in the creative department as the company has expanded globally. He has been an indispensable asset to the brand, as the voice, Creative and Copy Director, and overseeing other copywriters in all facets of the business. Our job is quite dynamic, interfacing with Product Development, Marketing, Package Designers and Art Directors, PR, E-commerce, and the President in order to maintain a consistent voice throughout any of our communication, branding, and untraditional advertising. One of his greatest talents is being able to turn difficult concepts into simple communication in tandem with keeping the message fresh, quirky, and Kiehl's. I would recommend Carmine to any brand, agency, or emerging company seeking someone to find their true voice in the marketplace."

— **Steve Marchione**, *Director of Global Copy & Brand Identity, Kiehl's Since 1851*, worked directly with Carmine at Kiehl's Since 1851

"Carmine has been a pillar of Kiehl's since 1851 for six years and his contribution to this company has had a profound impact to the success of Kiehl's as a whole. He is highly talented in everything that relates to brand DNA and positioning, and is excellent at translating an original idea into a powerful, customer-appealing project. He is a beauty product junkie and passionate about his work. On a day-to-day basis, he is a great colleague to be around, friendly, entertaining and fun, while keeping the priorities and getting things done. It was a great privilege to work with Carmine over these years and I recommend him wholeheartedly."

— Frederic Arbel, Director, Global Marketing, Kiehl's since 1851, L'Oreal, worked with Carmine at Kiehl's Since 1851

"Over the past year I have worked with Carmine on a variety of initiatives for Kiehl's and Shu Uemura retail stores. He is a quick, clever, diligent and witty. He has an understanding of how to communicate without compromising the brand's message and is flexible to the evolving needs of the business and the variety of the communications. Carmine is perhaps the soul of Kiehl's; he is deeply committed to the values of the brand and is committed to his team and to building consensus on where to take the brand in the future. His vision of Kiehl's via the messenging in direct mail pieces, email campaigns, labels and signage is fresh and always entertaining. On a personal note, he has an amazing sense of humor and everyone is drawn to him. I hope to work with him on many future Kiehl's projects."

— Daniela Rava, AVP-retail, Kiehl's Since 1851, worked with Carmine at Kiehl's Since 1851

"Carmine is an energetic and dedicated creative services marketing professional who is a real pleasure to work with. His passion to contribute in a brand building manner is consistently apparent and he is very open-minded to creative development optimization. In all of my encounters, he has demonstrated enthusiasm and focus to the creative development process as well as the branding mission at hand."

— Susan Lazar, *President, The Lazar Group. Qualitative Research. Insights. Strategy.*, worked indirectly for Carmine at Kiehl's Since 1851

"Carmine Montalto is a strong asset for any organization. He is a gifted writer and an orator. At Kiehl's, Carmine was a true ambassador for the company. During years of transition for the brand, he ensured that company's internal and external identity remained cohesive. The energy and humor that Carmine brought to all of his work made him such a treat to work with."

— Gracia Walker, Manager of Public Relations, Kiehl's Since 1851, worked directly with Carmine at Kiehl's Since 1851

"Carmine is an extremely talented copywriter and a passionate wordsmith. He immerses himself in the DNA of a brand and unlocks its inner voice. Working with Carmine has defined for me a new standard in copywriting and I would recommend him warmly."

— Marie-Pierre Stark-Flora, VP Global Marketing Development, Kiehl's since 1851, worked directly with Carmine at Kiehl's Since 1851

"Carmine Montalto has defined the voice of Kiehl's, making it an icon and truly unique worldwide brand. He has an incredible amount of passion for his work and for branding, a passion that moves everyone around him. His knowledge and command of languages and words, his beauty experience and most importantly, his uniqueness, will make Carmine a great asset in developing and reinforcing true brands."

— Martha Velando, *Group Marketing Manager*, *L'Oreal UK (Lancome)*, worked directly with Carmine at Kiehl's Since 1851

"Carmine pours an astonishing amount of passion, creativity, and life into the non-profit brands he helped to develop. His limitless energy and enthusiasm in his work reflects his wholehearted commitment to the Breast Cancer 3Day, AIDSRides, and the AIDS Vaccine Rides. His work helped set a lasting voice for national ad campaigns PTW launched year after year. Carmine also developed volumes of scripts, manuals, guidebooks, and even a quarterly magazine for participants. He was extremely instrumental in the success of the brands he shepherded. Carmine is an incredible asset to any creative team."

— Paiwei Wei, Design Director, Pallotta TeamWorks, worked directly with Carmine at Pallotta TeamWorks

Contact Carmine on LinkedIn